Guide to the Landon family papers 1977.025
Brooklyn Historical Society
- Series 3: Financial Records., 1759-1864; 1.0 Linear feet
  - Miscellaneous Financial - [Henry Landon] (1 of 3)., 1817-1839 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous Financial - [Henry Landon] (2 of 3)., 1840-1864 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous Financial - [Henry Landon] (3 of 3)., circa 1820-1860 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Hog Weights - [Henry Landon]., 1829-1852 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Series 4: Miscellaneous., 1757-1864; 0.25 Linear feet
  Material related to the Landons is followed by other material. Material likely to be that of Henry, but which does not explicitly refer to him, is foldered with his name in [brackets].
  Miscellaneous includes a broad mix of documents that defy broad categorization. The series includes documents related to Jared and Henry Landon which either did not clearly fit into the other series or had mixed content. The series includes Jared Landon's 1857 school workbook with arithmetic exercises and poetry, and which was also used in later decades for records of various accounts, a list of wills transmitted to New York, and an agreement among the heirs of Samuel Landon. Other material related to Jared includes a Revolution period character reference from a British officer and several printed New York State acts of legislation. Papers associated with Henry include a record of the heads of skunks and blackbirds presented to Henry for bounties. The bulk of Henry's papers in this series include documents that include a mix of matters (e.g., both financial and legal matters).
  Other material in the series from the American Revolution period includes an account by one Col. Popham of his part in the Battle of Long Island; an unsigned 1777 "Memoire," or reflection, on the development of the Revolution and its international implications; a transcription of a 1779 Congressional resolution; and Daniel Youngs's journal of his detention in the Provost prison during the Revolution (1778) and his writings from Connecticut. The series also includes a journal of the 1792 proceedings concerning a treaty with Indian nations from Wabash and Illinois country at Post Vincences, conducted by Brigadier General Rufus Putnam. Other items in the series are identified in the container list. The series closes with a few uncategorized items and fragments.
  - Landon, Jared., 1757-1802 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Landon, Henry., 1799-1826 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Documents with Mixed Content - [Henry Landon]., 1829-1848, undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - American Revolution., 1777-1779, undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Youngs, Daniel., 1778-1784 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    Transcriptions
    Transcriptions of the three documents in this folder can be found in the Brooklyn Historical Society's library, cataloged as Daniel Youngs' diary [1778-1784] / transcription by Edward P. Buffet (call number F127.L853.L66, Vol 5).
  - Journal and Proceedings of Indian Treaty at Post Vincences., 1792 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Description of Seashore from Boston to Annapolis Royal., 1735 (Box 5, Folder 19a)
  - Communication Concerning Post Office at 51 Wall St., 1791 (Box 5, Folder 19b)
  - Prizes Taken by Sloop Race Horse and Frigate Repulse., 1761 (Box 5, Folder 20a)
  - "Mournful Tragedy of Eliza Wells.", circa 1800 (Box 5, Folder 20b)
  - Pedlar Licenses; Advertisements., 1824-1849, undated (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous and Fragments., 1787-1864, undated (Box 5, Folder 22)